Guide to the Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
Fries, Waldemar H., Audubon research papers
- Series VII. Audubon Material
  - Audubon: Color Slides, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Audubon Genealogy and Chronology, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bank Note with Grouse. Includes Fries' correspondence, a copy of New Jersey Nature News, and The Essay Proof Journal, 1948, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Golden Eagle, in the Unpublished Letter of Audubon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Audubon and the Dolphin, in Auk, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Audubon Magazine - Letters, 1959-1958 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Maria R. Audubon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Audubon: Miscellaneous, 1830s, 1900s (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Audubon Painting - Nude in New Orleans, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Audubon - Stamp, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Audubon on the Habits of the Turkey Buzzard, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Agents, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Artist Criticism, 1800s, 1900s (Box 4, Folder 36A-B)
  - Audubon - Mason, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Obituaries, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Audubon Postcards, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Audubon: Letters of Introduction Carried on Missouri River Expedition, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Audubon Bibliography and Nomenclature of Ornithological Works, in Auk., 1906, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Books on Audubon, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Books Used by Audubon, 1800s, 1950-1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Audubon's Labrador Trip, in Auk, July 1919 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Audubon's Home in New York City, news clippings and Audubon Magazine, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Audubon - In the Florida Keys, in Natural History, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Audubon - Miscellaneous, 1860s, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - "Oakley" Audubon Memorial State Park, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Inventory of Collection of Audubonia at Audubon Memorial House, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Passenger List - SS George Washington, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 50A)
  - Audubon's Letters of Introduction, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 50B)
  - Audubon: Maps, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 50C)
  - Audubon: Journals, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 50D)
- Series VIII. Exhibitions: Catalogues and other Miscellany
  - Exhibitions: 1820 - 1840, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Edinburgh, Copy of catalogue of Mr. John J. Audubon's "Birds of America" being that portion of his collection now exhibiting at the Royal Edinburgh Institution. 1826
    Copy of Catalogue: Audubon's Original Drawings exhibited at the Lyceum of Natural History (396 drawings and also oils). 1839
  - Exhibitions: 1930 - 1949, 1930-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    The Whitney Museum of Art, New York, 8 - 30 March, 1932
    Original Audubon Prints lent by Harry P. Havell: An Exhibition at the Newark Museum, 1934
    The J. B. Speed Memorial Museum, Louisville, Kentucky; including both prints and original drawings. 3 - 5 February, 1935
    Library of the Congress (See Auk, July 1935 and letter from J. N. Edelstrin). July 1935
    Audubon Society of Rhode Island, The 150th Birth Anniversary of Audubon. April 26, 1935
    The Lakeside Press, R. R. Donnelley and Sons Company, Chicago, 40 prints exhibited. 1937
    The Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia: Copy of catalogue (Original), copy of original Catalogue (2 copies), additional information concerning ownership of materials exhibited. 26 April - 1 June, 1938
    The Museum of the Province of Quebec, Quebec City, from the William H. Coverdale Collection of Historical Candiana at the Manor Richelieu, Murray Bay, P.Q. 22 February - March 1944
  - Exhibitions: 1950 - 1955, 1950-1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Princeton University Library. 9 November - 9 December, 1950
    Princeton University Library, Memorandum and The Princeton University Chronicle. Winter 1951
    National Audubon Society, New York. 22 January - 25 February, 1951
    Worcester Art Museum. 6 May - 3 June, 1951
    National Audubon Society, New York, 2 catalogues, Portrait Painter. 28 May - 15 July, 1951
    National Audubon Society, New York, Quadrupeds. 16 October - 30 November, 1951
    The Library of Congress (See letter from Herbert J. Sanborn). 12 January, 1951
    The Reading Public Museum and Art Gallery. 29 April - 10 June, 1951
    Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University. 30 October - 14 December
    Lyman Allyn Museum, New London, Connecticut. 9 October - 11 November, 1951
    Kennedy Galleries Inc., New York. 5 - 26 November, 1951
    Newark Museum, Newark, N.J., prints loaned by Henry P. Havell. 1952
    Old Print Center, New York (Camelia Lucas), Audubon's Quadrupeds. 1953
    The Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, Memphis, Tenn., Audubon Sesquicentennial Exhibition. 26 April - 13 June, 1954
  - Exhibitions: 1959 - 1965, 1959-1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Princeton University Library, "The World of John James Audubon", printed catalogue compiled by Howard C. Rice, Jr., (Princeton university Chronicle, Autumn 1959 and Winter 1960). 15 May - September, 1959
    Cabildo, New Orleans, La. February - March 1960 (4 copies)
    Centre Culturel Americanin, Paris. October - November 1960
    Peabody Museum of Salem, Loring Gallery. October - November 1960
    Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University, "John J. Audubon, Alexander Wilson and others - Commemorating the 100th anniversary of the birth of John Eliot Taylor". 1962 (2 copies)
    Tampa Art institute, Tampa, Florida, "Audubon in Florida", organized by Robert O. Parks, curator of The John and Mabel Ringling Museum, Sarasota, Florida. 4 - 15 February, 1964
    Gainesville, Florida (also at Jacksonville and St. Petersburg, Florida), "Artists of the Florida Tropics: Audubon-Catlin-Homer-Innes". 1 - 31 March, 1965
    Munson-Williams_Proctor Institute, Utica, NY, "Audubon Watercolors and Drawings". 11 April - 30 May, 1965
    Pierpoint Morgan Library, "Audubon Watercolors and Drawings". 1 June - 30 July, 1965
    Audubon Memorial Museum, Henderson, KY, "John James Audubon's Quadrupeds". 1965
  - Exhibitions: 1962, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4B)
    Notes on the Princeton University Library exhibition, "The World of John James Audubon", 15 May - September, 1959. Includes photographs and descriptions of plates exhibited, and a marked copy of the exhibition catalogue.
  - Exhibitions: 1966 - 1974, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Louisiana State Museum - Friends of the Cabildo, New Orleans, La, "Audubon in Louisiana". 1966
    The New York historical Society, exhibition of 250 original drawings. November - December 1971
    The York Institute Museum, Saco, Maine. 16 September - 6 November 1971
    The New York Historical Society. 18 October, 1972 - February, 1973
    Museum of Science, Florida, catalogue for "Audubon in Florida", published by University of Miami Press. 1974
    Museum of Science, Miami, Florida. Audubon, a name that became a symbol. 15 - 31 March, 1974
    Cleveland Museum of Natural History. May 1974
  - Chronological Exhibition List, 1826-1974 and List of Exhibitions by John J. Audubon and his sons at the National Academy of Design, 1833-1949, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series IX. Auction Catalogues and Price-Lists
  - List of Catalogues and Price-Lists, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Case 1: Sotheby and Co. Includes Catalogues for:, 1959-1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    19th October, 1959. Includes final sale list
    2nd and 3rd July, 1962
    29th and 30th October, 1962
    4th and 5th November, 1963
    10th and 11th February, 1964
    24th May, 1965
    11th October, 1965
    28th November, 1966
    11th April, 1967
    6th December, 1967
    24th November, 1969. 4 copies, of which 1 includes inserted news clippings on the record price of sale of "The Birds of America"
    13th and 14th July, 1970. Includes final price list
    26th and 27th June, 1972. Includes inserted correspondence from Sotheby and Co.
    4th and 5th June, 1973. 2 copies, of which 1 includes final sale list
  - Case 2: Parke-Bernet Galleries (1946- 24th May 1966). Includes Catalogues for:, 1946-1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    18th and 19th November, 1946
    6th and 7th December 1947
    27th January, 1959
    24th November, 1959. 2 copies, of which 1 includes an inserted sheet of notes
    19th and 20th May, 1960
    January-February 1962. Monthly Bulletin
    30th January, 1962. 2 copies
    2nd and 3rd February, 1962
    15th and 16th January, 1963
    16th November, 1963
    14th May, 1966
    18th May, 1966. Includes final price list
    24th May, 1966. Includes final price list
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Includes Catalogues for:, 27th May 1966 - 1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Parke-Bernet Galleries. 27th May, 1966. Includes final price list
    Parke-Bernet Galleries. 1st November, 1966. Includes final price list
    Parke-Bernet Galleries. 16th April, 1968
    Parke-Bernet Galleries. 16th and 17th October, 1968. Includes final price list
  - Case 3: Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc; Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd. Includes Catalogues for:, 1961-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. 14th to 16th September, 1972. Includes copies of catalogue and final price list
    Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. 10th October, 1972. Includes inserted correspondence and final price list
    Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. 28th November, 1972. Includes inserted letter to Warren R. Howell
    Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. 29th May to 1st June, 1974. Includes price estimate list, and prices of Audubon plates sold on 29th May, 1974
    Christie's. 1961-1962, Review of the Year
    Christie's. May 1962, Forthcoming Sales
    Christie's. 30th May, 1962. Includes final price list
    Christie's. 18th February, 1964. Includes final price list
    Christie's. 13th March, 1971. Includes final price list
    Christie's. 12th April, 1972. Includes final price list
    Christie's. 10th and 11th October, 1972. Includes final price list
    Christie's. 9th May, 1973
  - Catalogues and Price Lists:, 1911-1923 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    C. F. Libbie and Company. 18th and 19th October, 1911. Includes an inserted slip of notes
    The Anderson Galleries. (Collection of Dr. William C. Braislin). 26th March, 1923.
  - Catalogues and Price Lists:, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    H.P. Kraus. (The Ninetieth Catalogue). ca 1959
    Bernard Quaritch Ltd. 1963. Includes a page of "The Book Collector"
    Charles W. Traylen. 10th to 20th June, 1964. Includes news clippings and notes
  - Catalogues and Price Lists:, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Charles Hamilton, 24 May 1967. Includes final price list
  - Catalogues and Price Lists:, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Samuel T. Freeman and Co. 30th June and 1st July, 1971
    J. N. Bartfield Books, Inc. 1972
    Hanzel Galleries, Inc. 21st and 22nd September, 1973. Includes final price list
  - Catalogues and Price Lists:, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Charles B. Wood III Inc. 1975.
    Wheldon and Wesley Limited. 1975
    Hanzel Galleries Inc. 9th to 12th March, 1975. Includes final price list
    Swann galleries Inc. May 1st, 1975. Includes final price list
    The Old Print Shop. May 1975.
  - Classified Advertisements:, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    The Clique, the Antiquarian Bookseller's Medium. 5th July, 1958
    Das Antiquariat, Zeitschrift fuer alle Fachgebiete des Buch- und Kunstantiquariats, No. 9/10, 1958. Includes sheets of correspondence (1958-1959) with Karl Krieg
- Series X. Publications and Reviews
  - "Where are Audubon's Copper Plates?", Audubon Magazine, July - August 1966 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "The Elephant Hunter", Audubon Magazine, September-October, 1958; "More Experiences of The Elephant Hunter", Audubon Magazine, January-February, 1963, 1958, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Reviews of "The Double Elephant Folio", 1974 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Reviews of "The Double Elephant Folio", 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 53B)
- Series XI. Art Work (Oversized): Audubon, John James; Audubon, Lucy; DeKay; Edwards; Peale; Wilson
  - List and Notes by Fries regarding Artwork donated to Cornell, ca. 1975 (Box 9, Folder ??)
  - AUDUBON, JOHN JAMES:
    - Original Print: Hudson Bay Titmouse, No. 39 Pl. CXIV, 1834 (Folder 1)
      Engraved, colored and printed by R. Havell
    - Reproduction: Largest White Billed Woodpecker (Folder 3)
      Beehive Press, Savannah, Georgia. Reproduced from The Natural History of Carolina, Florida and the Bahma Islands
    - Reproductions: Greenshank, Plate CCLXIX, ca 1950-1970 (Folder 3)
      Purchased by Fries at the Gift Shop at Fort St. Augustine, Florida
    - Reproduction: Great American Cock, Male, Pl. 1, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Reproduction: Summer Red Bird (Folder 3)
      Penn Prints, New York. Plate is designated as No. 42, Pl. 208, but the correct number is No. 9 Pl. 42
    - Reproduction: Red Shouldered Hawk, No. 12 Pl. LVI, 1963 (Folder 3)
      Macmillan reproduction. Printed in Switzerland. Edita Lausanne. Reverse is annotated by Fries.
    - Reproductions: 18 Best loved Paintings by Audubon, October 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Published by Book Enterprises Inc., New York. Includes famous Audubon paintings, listed on cover
    - Reproductions from the Heritage Reproductions of the Original Drawings in the New York Historical Society: (Box 12, Folder 3)
      1. Snowy Owl
      2. Snowy Egret
      3. Cedar Waxwing
      4. Pileated Woodpecker
      (5. and 6. in Map-case folder 1)
    - Reproductions of original Audubon drawings given to Edward Harri-Moorestown (Box 12, Folder 2)
      All of the originals are presently housed at the Houghton Library, Harvard University (except the Brown Thrasher, which may be at the Museum of Comparative Zoology). These drawings were used in "Bird Biographies of John James Audubon selected by Alice Ford", Macmillan Co. 1957. The reproductions include:
      1. White-throated Sparrow
      2. Fish Hawk (Osprey)
      3. Passenger Pigeon
      4. Carolina Parrot
      5. Yellow-billed Cuckoo
      6. Screech Owl (Red Owl)
      7. Whip-poor-will
      8. Belted Kingfisher
      9. Ivory-billed Woodpecker
      10. Brown Thrasher
      11. Norther Shrike
      12. Unnamed Bird (Probably Willet)
    - Reproductions from the Old Print Shop, New York(Originals courtesy of Harry Shaw Newman): (Box 12, Folder 2)
      1. No. 3 Pl. 12: Baltimore Oriole
      2. No. 18 Pl. 87: Florida Jay
      3. No. 42 Pl. CCVI: Summer or Wood Duck
    - Reproductions of Audubon prints from the Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company. Donelley Press: (Box 12, Folder 1)
      1. No. 20 Pl. 96: Columbia Jay
      2. No. 9 Pl. 42: Orchard Oriole
      3. No. 7 Pl. 33: Yellow Bird or American Goldfinch
      4. No. 10 Pl. 46: Barred Owl
      5. No. 32 Pl. CLIX: Cardinal Grosbeak
      6. No. 74 Pl. CCCLXVI: Iceland or Jer Falcon
      7. No. 87 Pl. CCCXXXI: American Flamingo
      8. No. 35 Pl. CLXXIII: Barn Swallow
      9. No. 12 Pl. XCI: Broad-winged Hawk
      10. No. 32 Pl. CLVI: American Crow
      11. No. 21. PL. CL: Raven
      12. No. 27 Pl. CXXXI: American Robin
    - Reproductions of 30 Audubon prints, Harry N. Abrams Inc., New York:, September 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7-9)
      (Fries compared these with the Lownes originals on 17 September 1964. All prints are annotated on the reverse. The paintings are arranged in the following order in folders 6-8)
      Pl. 1: Wild Turkey
      Pl. 12: Baltimore Oriole
      Pl. 17: Carolina Pigeon
      Pl. 26: Carolina Parrot
      Pl. 53: Painted Finch
      Pl. 62: Passenger Pigeon
      Pl. 77: Belted Kingfisher
      Pl. 82: Whip-poor-will
      Pl. 87: Florida Jay
      Pl. 91: Broad-winged Hawk
      Pl. 97: Little Screech Owl
      Pl. 102: Blue Jay
      Pl. 107: Canada Jay
      Pl. 111: Pileated Woodpecker
      Pl. 128: Cat Bird
      Pl. 136: Meadowlark
      Pl. 137: Yellow-breasted Chat
      Pl. 159: Cardinal Grosbeak
      Pl. 206: Summer or Wood Duck
      Pl. 211: Great Blue Heron
      Pl. 217: Louisiana Heron
      Pl. 221: Mallard Duck
      Pl. 250: Arctic Tern
      Pl. 251: Brown Pelican
      Pl. 313: Blue-winged Teal
      Pl. 357: American Magpie
      Pl. 366: Iceland or Jer Falcon
      Pl. 367: Band-tailed Pigeon
      Pl. 406: Trumpeter Swan
      Pl. 431: American Flamingo
      Booklet "The Audubon Folio", by George Dock, Jr. is in Map-case F-7, folder 11.
    - Reproductions from the Heritage Reproductions of the Original Drawings in the New York Historical Society (Continued): (Folder 1)
      5. Red-throated Loon
      6. Bald Eagle
    - Reproduction: Bat-tailed Grackle, No. 38 Pl. CLXXXVII, 1937 (Folder 1)
      Engraved, printed and coloured by A.P.P. Co. Inc., New York
    - Reproduction: Ruffed Grouse, Pl. XIL (Folder 1)
      J. B. Fisher Co. New York. Genuine Craft Print.
    - Reproduction: American Flamingo, No 87, Pl. CCCCXXXI, 1950 (Folder 1)
      "Centennial Audubon Prints", History Institute of America Inc., Locust Valley, NY. Hand-colored copper plate etching reproduced by special permission of The American Museum of Natural History.
    - Exhibition Poster: American Flamingo., 1960 (Folder 1)
      Tittled "John James Audubon 1785-1851". The Exhibition ran from 19th October to 10th December 1960
    - Calendar: Northwestern Life Insurance Company., 1958-1959 (Folder 2)
    - Educational Poster: "Birds: Nature's Protectors" (Folder 2)
      Church and Dwight Co., New York. Includes detailed plans for the inclusion of the chart in classroom study for school children
    - "The Audubon Folio", by George Dock, Jr., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Harry N. Abrams Inc., New York. Accompanying text to 30 reproductions made by the company
    - Prospectus: Ariel Press, London, 1972 (Folder 3)
      Prospectus calls for subscriptions to a facsimile edition of 20 selected plates, limited to 250 copies in the USA, priced at $350
    - Prospectus: Beehive Press, Savannah, Georgia, 1972 (Folder 3)
      Prospectus calls for subscriptions to a reproduction of The Natural history of Carolina, Florida, and the Bahama Islands by Mark Catesby (MCMLXII). 2 copies
    - Forest and Stream, Vol. XXX - No. 8, 9 February 1888 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Pg 58: Re-sale of Audubon Octavo prints.
    - Frame: Reproduction of Plate #251: Brown Pelican (Box 12)
      From the print of th folio at the National Audubon Society, New York; with a silver ingot.
    - Frame: 20c Airmail stamp sheet of Audubon's painting of the Columbia Jay (Box 12)
    - Postage Stamps: 1c Sheet, 5c Sheet, 20c Airmail Sheet (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Audubon Slides - Birds of America and others (Box 9)
      A list of these 50 color slides, produced by (jointly) the National Audubon Society and the National Gallery of Art, Washington D.C. and others, can be found along with the slides.
  - AUDUBON, LUCY:
    - Original Print: Swamp Sparrow, No. 13 Pl. LXIV, 1831 (Folder 1)
      Engraved, colored and printed by R. Havell. J Whatman Watermark.
  - DeKAY, JAMES ELSWORTH:
    - Four sheets from the Zoology of New York, Part II: (Box 12, Folder 5)
      1. Pl. 26 Fig. 56: Cedar Bird
      2. Pl. 26 Fig. 57: Bohemian Waxwing
      3. Pl. 62 Fig. 142: Pine Bull Finch
      4. Pl. 62 Fig. 143: Cardinal Grosbeak
      5. Pl. 79 Fig. 179: Ring Plover
      6. Pl. 79 Fig. 180: Black-breasted Snipe
      7. Pl. 79 Fig. 181: Killdeer
      8. Pl. 80 Fig. 182: Turnstone
      9. Pl. 80 Fig. 183: Oyster-catcher
  - EDWARDS, GEORGE:
    - Spotted Plower from North America, 1748 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - PEALE, TITEAN:
    - Wild Turkey, Male and Female. (Folder 3)
      From "American Ornithology or the Natural History of Birds inhabiting the United States -not given by Wilson - with figures drawn, engraved and coloured, from Nature, by Charles Lucien Bonaparte, Vol I".
  - WILSON, ALEXANDER:
    - Original Print: White-headed Eagle, ca 1830 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Pl. 36, from "American Ornithology - The Natural History of the United States Illustrated with Plates Engraved and Coloured from Original Drawings taken from Nature, Vol V."
      From "American Ornithology", 1820:
      1. Pl. 57: Turnstone, Ash-coloured Sandpiper, Purre, Black-bellied Plover, Red-breasted Sandpiper
      2. Pl. 58: Red-breasted Snipe, Long-legged Avoset, Solitary Sandpiper, Tell-tale Snipe
      3. Pl. 64: Louisiana Heron, Pied Oyster-catcher, Hooping Crane, Long-billed Curlew
    - Original Prints from "American Ornithology", ca 1820 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Series XII. Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence and Forms: Veterans Administration, 1919, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 81)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
The following books have been removed from the collection and many are now cataloged separately. They may be found using the online library catalog.
The AOU Check list of North American Birds, Fifth Edition by American Ornithologists Union
Published: Baltimore, Lord Baltimore Press, 1957
Notes by Fries: Named in ink, 1958
Audubon, An Intimate Life of the American Woodsman by Arthur, Stanley Clisby
Published: New Orleans, Harmanson, 1937
Notes by Fries: Notes on cover referencing page nos; Includes full color map
The Salem Anthenaeum, 1810-1910 by Ashton, Joseph Nickerson
Published: Salem, Mass, [Berkeley Press], 1917
Notes by Fries: Note referncing pg. no on cover.
Audubon Birds, from the Original Water Colors in the New York Historical Society by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Hastings House, 1946
Notes by Fries: Notes on multiple pages, marking Audubon plate nos.
Audubon in the West; Compiled, edited, and with an introduction by Elliott Coues by Audubon, John James
Published: London, J.C. Nimmo, 1898
Notes by Fries: Includes a loose, inserted book review.
Audubon, by Himself; A profile of John James Audubon from writings selected, arranged and edited by Alice Ford. by Audubon, John James
Published: Garden City, NY, Natural History Press, 1969
Audubon's America; The Narratives and Experiences of John James Audubon, edited by Donald Culross Peattie; illustrated with facsimiles of Audubon's prints and paintings by Audubon, John James
Published: Boston, Houghton Mifflin, 1940
Audubon's American Birds; from plates by J. J. Audubon. With an introduction and notes on the plates by Sacheverell Sitwell. by Audubon, John James
Published: London, NY, Batsford, 1949
Notes by Fries: Includes typewritten notes on the book on front cover, first page named in ink.
Audubon's Animals: The Quadrupeds of North America, compiled and edited by Alice Ford by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Studio Publications in association with Cowell, 1951
Notes by Fries: None; includes Ex libris card
Audubon's Wildlife. With selections from the writings of John James Audubon, edited by Edwin Way Teale. by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Viking Press, 1964
Notes by Fries: None; includes citation in ink, and taped price list
Bird Biographies. Selected and Edited by Alice Ford by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Macmillan, 1957
Notes by Fries: Includes a review, and Ex libris card
Birds of America, by John James Audubon, with a foreword and descriptive captions by William Vogt by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Macmillan, 1944
Notes by Fries: Review taped on front page, ex libris card.
Birds of America. Introduction and Descriptive captions by Ludlow Griscom. Poular Edition. by Audubon, John James
Published: New York, Macmillan, 1950
Notes by Fries: None. Ex libris card
Imperial Collection of Audubon Animals; the quadrupeds of North America. Original Text by John James Audubon and John Bachman. Edited with new text by Victor H. Chalane. Foreword by Fairfield Osborn. Illustrated by John James Audubon and John Woodhouse Audubon by Audubon, John James
Published: Maplewood, NJ, Hammond, 1967
Notes by Fries: none; has a letter used as abookmark, possibly from previous owner
Letters of John James Audubon, 1826-1840, eidted by Howard Corning. Vol I-II by Audubon, John James
Published: Boston, The Club of Odd Volumes. 1929
Notes by Fries: None.